RYAN WORKMAN

Summary

I am a software developer who learned the tools of the trade from the Turing School of Software and Design. After spending five years working as a news producer for local stations across the country, I decided to pursue my passion for creating cool things and solving problems. Over the past seven months, I have dove head first into learning Ruby and excelling to the top of my class. There is nothing I love more than scouring docs and continuing to grow my skills and knowledge to make the best programs possible.

Employment

Trelora
Full-Stack Web Developer Internship

Denver, CO Dec 2016 to Current

- Developed new features for their internal file-saving API including ripping out Box and replacing it AWS S3.
- Enhanced the company's internal signage app to handle custom slides using a simple form and auto-formatting algorithm
- Worked closely with CTO Keith Hunniford and his team working through complex problems with consolidating two codebases

KDVR Fox31 Denver

News Producer

Denver, CO Jul 2014 to Jun 2016

- Responsible for producing the 5:00 PM Saturday and Sunday newscasts.
- Lead reporters, anchors, directors and editors on a daily basis to achieve the station's goal of
 growing the ratings on the weekend while upholding the standards our viewers have come to
 expect.
- Produced Fox31's aggressive Broncos post-game show.

KPTV Fox 12 Oregon

News Producer

Portland, OR Aug 2012 to May 2014

- Produced 4:30 to 6:00 of the number one rated Good Day Oregon every morning Monday through Friday.
- Took the initiative to grow my skills while strengthening Good Day Oregon by creating several elements in my show that have had a positive reception including Good Day Pets.
- Stacked, wrote and completed the 90 minute newscast every morning.

KALB News Channel 5

News Producer

Alexandria, LA Sep 2011 to Jul 2012

- Produced the 6:00 pm and 10:00 pm shows for News Channel Five (KALB) in Alexandria, Louisiana.
- Created several stingers and promotional graphics for the station that aired on a weekly basis.

Projects

NewZ - Connecting local news producers with the communities they serve

My two-week personal project for Turing School of Software & Design. I created a web application that allows viewers and news producers to have an open dialogue about stories important to them. The application utilizes the New York Times API to generate trending stories and CronJobs calling Rake Tasks to hit the API from the server. My main focus on this project was server management utilizing Capistrano to deploy the app to a DigitalOcean server.

Site: NewZapp.net

GitHub: https://github.com/rdavid1099/newZ

Acquire-A-Hire - Application Clone Project

A two-week group project for Turing School of Software & Design. My four person group set out to construct of clone of Thumbtack. We created a website that allowed professionals and requesters to connect pitching jobs and bidding for offers. I focused on DevOps for the group, launching my first DigitalOcean server and utilizing NGinX to maximize performance.

Site: http://159.203.116.158/

GitHub: https://github.com/susiirwin/acquire_a_hire

Contact

- **(303) 815-0866**
- **♥** Denver. CO
- f ryan.workman.5243
- **→** ProducerWorkman
- in /in/ryan-workman
- rdavid1099

Education

Turing School of Software & Design

Certificate Web Application
Development, Ruby/Rails/JS 2017

University of Northern Colorado

B.A. Journalism and Mass Communication 2011

Skills

WEB DEVELOPMENT

Ruby

Rails

JavaScript

Capistrano

Server Management/ DevOps

Active Record/ SOL

LEADERSHIP

Team Leadership

Producing

Creative Strategy

JOURNALISM

Broadcast Journalism

Breaking News

Adobe Creative Suite